我叫巴里·艾伦  是现今世上速度最快的人
My name is Barry Allen, and I am the fastest man alive.
在外人看来  我只是个普通的鉴证专员
To the outside world, I'm an ordinary forensic scientist,
但在尖端科研实验室的朋友们的帮助下
but secretly, with the help of my friends at S.T.A.R. Labs,
我秘密地打击犯罪  寻找跟我一样的超能力者
I fight crime and find other meta-humans like me.
我让杀害母亲的凶手自食其果
I hunted down the man who killed my mother,
但我们的世界也因此出现了新的威胁
but in doing so, I opened up our world to new threats,
我是唯一来得及阻止他们的人
and I am the only one fast enough to stop them.
我叫闪电侠
I am The Flash.
《闪电侠》前情回顾
Previously on the Flash..
你们为什么没给我起个代号呢
How come you haven't given me a code name?
你觉得我该叫什么
What do you think I should be called?
金色滑翔者
Golden Glider.
聪明就是性感  西斯科
Smart is sexy, Cisco.
你为什么不直接杀了我
Why didn't you just kill me?
你现在也欠我一份人情了
Well, I guess you owe me one now too.
我叫杰伊·加里克
My name Jay Garrick.
在我的世界里  我也是个极速者
Where I came from, I was a speedster, like you.
当你在中城制造了奇点
When you created the Singularity above Central City,
你也在我们两个世界之间制造了一个缺口
you also created a portal connecting our two earths.
我不知怎么就到了你们的世界
I somehow ended up in your world.
缺口不止一个  一共有52个
There isn't just one breach. There's 52 of them.
而最显著的缺口
But the most significant breach of all
就在这里  尖端科研实验室
appears to be here, inside S.T.A.R. Labs.
爱瑞丝  怎么了
Hey, Iris. What's up?
巴里  我需要你的帮助  就现在
Barry, I need your help, now!
-那是枪声吗  -是
- Were those gunshots? - Yeah.
我在鲍德温塔  我出不去
I'm at Baldwin Tower! I can't find a way out.
窗...有窗吗
Window-- is there window?
在这儿
Over here!
就在前面
Um, yeah, up ahead.
我在窗边了  要怎么做
Okay, I'm by the window. Why?
很好  你从窗户跳下去
Okay, great, you're gonna need to jump.
什么  你疯了吗  巴里  不行的
What? Are you crazy? Barry, no way.
爱瑞丝  你相信我吗
Iris! Do you trust me?
我相信你
Yes. I trust you.
那就跳下去
Okay, then jump.
我可以的  我可以的
I can do this. I can do this.
-你还好吗  -还好
- All right. You good? - Yeah.
好  等下  上面有几个人
All right. Wait, uh... how many guys are up there?
两个  都有枪
Uh, two. They both have guns.
现在他们晕过去了  等中城警局叫醒他们
Okay, now they're taking little naps till the CCPD wakes them.
你到底在想什么
So what exactly were you thinking?
我拿到了关于房地产骗局的第一手资料
I got a hot lead on a real estate scam.
这些人一直非法驱逐住客
I mean, these guys have been illegally evicting people,
拆散别人家庭
breaking up families.
听着  没有什么新闻值得你把命搭上
Okay, look, no story is worth your life.
谢谢你来救我
Thank you for coming!
我等不及要把这写下来
I can't wait to write about this.
太神奇了  不是吗
Pretty amazing, isn't it?
还是不敢相信自己看到的东西
Still can't believe what I'm looking at.
中城52个缺口  最大的
52 breaches in Central City, and the biggest one
恰好就在我们的地下室
just happens to be in our basement.
-我们要给它取个名字  -这又不是个宠物  西斯科
- We need a name for it. - It's not a pet, Cisco.
确实不是  是个虫洞
No, it's a wormhole.
斯泰因教授  你在做什么
Professor Stein, what are you doing?
你的血压  上压147下压82
Your blood pressure is 147 over 82!
你可能会再次晕厥
You could pass out again.
到我这年纪比140高一点没什么
Oh, it's merely a few points above the 140 average for someone my age.
再说我有些想法
Besides, I have some ideas
我想参与探讨  斯诺博士
I would like to contribute to this discussion, Dr. Snow.
我也想听
And I want to hear them.
这不只是个虫洞  这是我回家的路
This isn't just a wormhole. It's my way home.
回地球二号
Back to Earth Two.
杰伊  你真的觉得我们可以把这个虫洞
Jay, you really think that we can use this
当作连接我们两个世界的桥梁吗
as some kind of bridge from your world to ours?
极速就用了这些缺口  我们为什么不能
Zoom uses the breaches. Why can't we?
我们不会用
We don't know how.
我放进去的东西全都弹回来了
Everything I put through just bounces back.
如果极速用这些缺口  从地球二号送人过来
If Zoom's using these breaches to transport people
那可能需要极速者
from Earth Two, maybe it takes a speedster.
-他不会是要...  -没错
- He's not gonna-- - Yeah, he is.
或许我还不够快
Maybe I'm not fast enough.
我不觉得光有速度
I don't believe your speed
就能行得通  巴里
is the entirety of the issue, Barry.
可能和缺口的稳定性
It might be the breach's stability
-或者不稳定性有关  -他说的对
- or lack thereof. - He's right.
我们要把它看成一扇门
We need to think of the breach as a door,
在地球二号  还有一扇门
and on Earth Two, there's another door.
两扇门之间  有个通道
In between, we have a hallway,
但是通道时刻在变化
but the hallway's constantly shifting,
在扭曲  在自我重叠
twisting, collapsing upon itself.
门会随之变化
And the doors keep moving with it.
我们要使门稳定  通道也就会稳定
So we stabilize the door, we stabilize the hallway.
然后就能跳进去了
And then I can jump through it.
对  就像一种发射炮
Exactly, it would serve as a kind of cannon.
神速炮
A speed cannon.
我们该多多泡在一起
Mm. We should hang out more.
好  今天不再做测试了
All right. No more tests today.
你们都出去吧  我也出去
All of you are leaving now, as am I.
珍惜年轻
Cherish the gift of youth
我要珍惜一下严重缺失的睡眠
as I will go cherish my much needed nap.
克莱丽莎已经在过来接我的路上
Clarissa's already on her way to pick me up.
乔瑟夫
Joseph.
你戴着结婚戒指
You're wearing your wedding ring.
离了婚的男人会摘下  鳏夫可不会
Divorced men take them off. Widowers don't.
我需要你离开中城
I need you to leave town.
你觉得你可以给我钱
And you thought you could pay me
让我离开我女儿吗
to walk away from my own daughter?
上一次  你一毛钱没得就离开了
Last time, you walked away for free.
多少钱也不能让我离开爱瑞丝
No amount of money is gonna keep me away from Iris.
20年了  弗朗辛
It has been 20 years, Francine.
现在你为什么来
Why did you show up now?
现在的我和以前不同了
Now I'm different.
现在我准备好了
Now I'm ready.
不  现在  你已经太迟了
No. Now you're too late.
爱瑞丝没有你也过得很好
Iris is fine without you.
你做得..
You've done--
你做得很好  乔
You've done a wonderful job, Joe.
比我能够做的要好得多
Better then I ever could,
但现在  她需要母亲
but right now, she needs her mother.
缺失生命里的挚爱
Losing the love of your life isn't something
不是几个月能弥补的
you can just get over in a few months.
我知道
I would know.
是吗
Would you?
你有48小时的时间离开中城
You have 48 hours to leave Central City.
我哪也不去
I'm not going anywhere.
是闪电侠啊
Hey! The Flash!
什么
What?
他们今天的今日特饮
The drinks that they're serving today.
它们就叫闪电侠
They're called the Flash.
就是多加一份浓咖啡的特调咖啡
A brewed coffee with an extra shot of espresso
能让你整日精神充沛
to keep you running all day.
不过我看你喝一杯就够了
But you should maybe just, you know, have one of those.
这些是我朋友点的
Yeah, no, my--my friends, uh, ordered these.
我都不知道
I didn't even realize--
你要留下来跟我们一起庆祝吗
are you sticking around to celebrate?
我不知道  我要留下来吗
I don't know, should I?
我看还是算了吧
You know, actually, never mind, I can't.
我要去上班了
I have to head into work.
-那好吧  -很高兴见到你
- Okay. - But it was great to see you.
-很高兴见到你  -再见
- Yeah, good to see you. - Okay, bye.
再见  帕蒂
Bye, Patty.
给  四杯闪电侠
All right, four Flashes.
你们还是悠着点  里面的咖啡因多着呢
Be careful--apparently, they are super-caffeinated.
先是给我个纪念日  现在都有饮品了
First I have a day named after me. Now I have a drink.
考虑到你做了这么多  重建了这里
Well, all the things you do, rebuilding this place,
保护无辜的市民  大家都很感激你
protecting people, everyone's appreciative, right?
-那就为这个干杯吧  -来吧
- Mm-hmm, I'll drink to that. - Yeah.
你们说斯泰因教授应该没事吧
Hey, you guys think Professor Stein is okay, right?
要是出事了克莱丽莎肯定会打电话来
I mean, Clarissa would call if there was anything wrong.
-对啊  -好吧
- Yeah. - All right.
我还是打个电话过去吧
I'm just gonna call and check in.
一会儿回来
I'll be back.
我看这个电话不会有什么好下场
I don't see that call going well.
年轻小姐
Young lady,
老是打电话过来是很烦人的
these repeated intrusions are interrupting
要想快速康复...
what should be a speedy recov--
抱歉
Oh, I'm so sorry.
不用抱歉
Don't apologize.
你随时可以撞我  西斯科
You can bump into me any day, Cisco.
丽萨·史纳特
Lisa Snart.
你是又来出卖我们的
You here to double-cross us again,
还是说你和你哥哥对咖啡店感兴趣了
or are you and your big bro holding up coffee shops now?
我需要你们的帮助
I need your help.
想得美  寒冷小姐  我应该打给闪电侠
In your dreams, Sister Cold. You know I could call The Flash.
他估计两秒  一秒就能赶过来
He'd be here in like two seconds--probably one.
打给他吧
Call him.
好啊  现在我就打给他
Oh, okay. I'm gonna call him. Mm-hmm.
你真的想让我打电话给闪电侠
You really want me to call The Flash?
我也需要他的协助
I need his help too.
我哥哥被绑架了
My brother's been kidnapped.
你觉得我们会相信
All right, so you really want us
寒冷队长被绑架了吗
to just believe that Captain Cold was kidnapped?
我亲眼看见的
I saw it happen.
昨晚  兰尼  我还有米克
Last night, Lenny, me, and Mick
正在翻中城赛马场的收银柜
were knocking over the cashier's cage at Central City Racetrack.
是不是一天不抢劫
Does it physically pain your family
你们家的人就难受啊
not to rob people?
我还没抢完呢
I never finished the job.
在米克把侧通道烧了之后
After Mick torched through the side entrance,
我回头去找兰尼  看见他被人拖进了一辆面包车
I looked back for Lenny and saw him getting thrown into the back of a van.
那你和米克为什么不跟上去呢
And why didn't you and Mick follow?
我是要跟去的
I would have.
有人从背后袭击我  把我击昏了
Someone hit me from behind and knocked me out.
等我醒来  兰尼不见了
When I came to, Lenny was gone,
米克带着钱逃跑了
and Mick already made off with the cash.
你要怎么证明这不是你们的陷阱
How do we know this isn't some kind of a trap?
如果兰尼想要闪电侠死
If Lenny wanted Flash dead,
他早就让马登  西蒙斯和巴布洛
he would have let Mardon, Simmons, and Bivolo
早早就把他干掉了  还记得吗
take that honor, remember?
-我还记得  -很好
- Yeah, I remember. - Good.
那你应该记得  你欠兰尼一次救命人情
Then you'll also recall that you owe Lenny a favor for saving your life.
闪电侠  是时候还这个人情了
Time to make good on that debt, Flash.
我不喜欢她
I do not like her.
不过她说的有道理
Yeah, but she makes a point.
怎么了  好歹让她说完吧
What? We should at least hear her out.
对不对
Right?
就算我想帮你  我们要怎么找到你哥哥
Even if I wanted to help, how are we supposed to find him?
小菜一碟
Not a problem.
当我重塑冷冻枪的时候
See, when I rebuilt the cold gun,
我来不及在里面放追踪器
I didn't have time to place a tracker on it,
所以我借用军方技术  发明了一个追踪方法
so I devised a method of locating it by borrowing some military technology.
冷冻枪的原理和热成像是一样的
See, the gun works the same as thermal imaging,
扫瞄频率中
热成像一般是寻找红外线热能
only instead of infrared heat signatures,
我把她改成了寻找紫外线冷能
it's looking for ultraviolet cold signatures.
看看这个
Whoa, look at that.
八分钟前在第五大街和霍伊特大街交界处
The gun's UV thermal reading was last picked up
最后一次检测到枪的UV指数
at 5th and Hoyt eight minutes ago.
好吧  我就看看你是不是在骗我
All right. Let's see if you're a liar.
史纳特
Snart.
巴里
Barry.
你还好吗
Are you okay?
很好
Peachy.
那就好
Okay.
我是来救你的
Uh, I'm supposed to be here to rescue you.
我不需要你救
That's not necessary.
你可以走了
You can speed along now.
史纳特  如果这些人强迫你
Look, Snart, if these guys are making you do this--
没人强迫我
No one makes me do anything.
那为什么你妹妹说你被绑架了
Then why does your sister think you've been kidnapped?
你怎么弄了这么久
What's taking so long?
有点事
I got held up.
你就会找借口
Always the excuse with you.
看看这个
Look at that.
没想到你还有这手啊  儿子
I didn't think you had it in you, son.
谢谢  老爸
Thanks, Dad.
来吧
Come on.
我们已经落后了
We're behind schedule.
你知道他们怎么说的
You know what they say.
来去匆匆  英年早逝
You live fast, die young?
跟我说说  发生了什么
Talk to me. What's going on?
西斯科  史纳特用冷冻枪打中了我
Cisco! Snart hit me with his cold gun.
他的生命指数要见底了
His vitals are bottoming out!
我要要开始加热了
I'm bringing the heat right now.
什么
What?
这衣服  发生了什么
The suit. What's happening?
热能线  亲爱的
Therma-threading, baby.
是我加入的新功能
It's a little something I added
专为这种情况准备的
for situations exactly like this one.
请告诉我它起作用了
Please, please tell me it's working.
是起作用了  但是史纳特跑了
Yeah, it works, but Snart's gone,
丽萨要好好的解释下了
and Lisa has a lot of explaining to do.
其实你哥哥没有被绑架
So your brother was not kidnapped.
他是在和你父亲干活
He was pulling a job with your father.
什么
What?
不可能  兰尼绝对不会这么做
No, Lenny would never do that.
是吗  就像是他绝不会
Oh, just like he would never
试图用冷冻枪杀死闪电侠吗
try and kill The Flash with his cold gun.
你确定是我父亲吗
Are you sure it was my dad?
中城警局
就是他
That's him.
路易斯·史纳特
Lewis Snart.
犯盗窃罪  持枪抢劫
Convicted of larceny, armed robbery,
故意伤害  使用致命武器攻击他人
aggravated assault, assault with a deadly weapon.
你要相信我  史纳特绝不会和他合作
You have to believe me. Lenny would never work with him.
他是个坏人
He's a bad guy.
你和你的整个家族都是罪犯
You and your entire family are criminals.
我们为什么要相信你的话
Why should we trust anything you say?
我这个伤疤不是因为犯罪而来的
I didn't get this scar being a criminal.
是做他女儿而来的
I got it being a daughter.
让我来  我能解决
Let me go. I got this.
看来你发现了我的藏身之地
I see you found my hiding spot.
这里是我经常来
This is usually where I come
你知道  躲避的地方
to, you know, get away.
我父亲第一次冲我来的时候
First time my father came after me,
我才七岁
I was seven.
第二次  我八岁
Second time, I was eight.
那一次我知道了瓶子比拳头打得痛
That's when I learned that a bottle hurts worse than a fist.
他总是说要给我们上一课
He used to say he was trying to teach us lessons.
我的学习能力一定很差
I must have been a slow learner,
因为课程一直没有停下
because the lessons never stopped.
很抱歉  丽萨
I'm sorry, Lisa.
基本上是兰尼养大的我
Lenny practically raised me.
如果不是他  我会变得更加糟糕
If it weren't for him, I would have turned out a lot worse.
我知道  我还能变得多糟
I know, how could I be any worse?
我没有那么说
I didn't say that.
你不需要说出来
You didn't have to.
但相信我  会变得更糟的
But believe me, there is worse.
而且  他可能是个混蛋哥哥
And, look, he may be a jerk brother,
但也是我唯一的混蛋哥哥
but he's the only jerk brother I've got.
他保护过我
He protected me.
现在轮到我了
Now it's my turn.
如果他和我父亲一起
If he's with my dad,
他的麻烦可就大了
he is in serious trouble.
求你了
Please.
你一定要搞清楚是怎么回事
You've gotta find out what's going on.
中城新闻图报
好啊  宝贝
Hey, baby.
爸爸
Dad!
你来这干什么
What are you doing here?
来看看我最喜欢的抗击犯罪记者
Came to check in on my favorite crime-fighting reporter.
爸
Dad!
其实  有件事我得和你谈谈
Actually, there's something I need to talk to you about.
爱瑞丝
Hey, Iris.
编辑部需要尽快拿到你的照片和报道
Editorial needs your photos and story ASAP.
恭喜你  警探
Congratulations, Detective.
你女儿的爆料上头版了
Your daughter's expos just made the front page.
真的吗
What?
我太为你感到高兴了
I am so happy for you.
还有点嫉妒  但这劲会过去的
A little bit jealous, but I'll get over it.
谢谢你  琳达  我是运气好
Thanks, Linda. I got lucky.
不是  她这是谦虚呢
No, she's being modest.
你的女儿真的是太厉害了
Your daughter's a serious badass.
这不用你说的
You don't have to tell me.
那最好让你回去工作了
Well, better let you get back to work.
等下  你有些事想告诉我  是吗
Wait, there was something that you wanted to talk to me about, right?
下回吧  不急的  去闪光吧
Later, it can wait. Go be fabulous.
好吧
Okay.
这么快就死而复生了吗  巴里
Back from the dead so soon, Barry?
把盐递给我
Pass me the salt.
别撒了  走霉运
Don't spill. It's bad luck.
你为什么要和路易斯合作
Why are you working with Lewis?
丽莎和我们说你恨他
Lisa told us you hate him.
这事...
Things are...
我家里的事挺复杂的
complicated with family,
就像是你和你父母一样
as you know with your own parents, hmm?
告诉我发生了什么
Tell me what's going on.
让我帮助你
Let me help you.
别浪费时间去拯救那些
Don't waste your time trying to save people
不想被拯救的人
who don't want to be saved.
也许这事情不只关系到你  好吗
Yeah, well, maybe it's not just about you, all right?
我打赌  不管你们俩想干什么
I'm betting whatever you two are up to,
都会有无辜的人受到伤害
innocent people are gonna get hurt.
别担心  我记得咱俩的交易
Don't worry, I remember our deal.
你别管我  我确保不会有人死
You leave me alone, I make sure no one dies.
好吧
All right.
你是个罪犯  史纳特
You're a criminal, Snart,
但是你有自己的准则
but you live by a code.
而据我所知路易斯没有
It sounds to me like Lewis doesn't,
他可不管别人的死活
like he won't care if people die.
这就是为什么我不能撒手不管
That's why I can't leave this alone.
那所有人都会知道面具下的闪电侠是谁
Then everyone will know who The Flash is under that mask.
我不在乎
I don't care.
我还是会抓住你们俩
I will take you down anyway. Both of you.
等着瞧吧
We'll see about that.
谢谢你请客
Thanks for dinner.
乔·韦斯特
来电
爱瑞丝的妈妈还活着
Iris' mom is alive.
我骗了爱瑞丝  你  所有人
I lied to Iris, you, everybody.
为什么
Why?
我觉得我没有选择
I felt like I didn't have a choice.
弗朗辛做了太多的错事
Francine did so many things wrong.
没有一件是对的
Just about everything.
我不知道
I don't know.
现在感觉我做的这件错事可能是最糟糕的
Now I feel like my one wrong might be worse.
听我说  乔
Look, Joe.
我从小就认识你了
I've known you for, you know, most of my life,
而我知道你做出的决定
and I know that you always have a good reason
都是有正当理由的
for the decisions you make.
很显然  你当时担心
And obviously, you were worried
爱瑞丝被弗朗辛养大会走上同样的错路
that Iris would go down the wrong path if Francine raised her.
看看史纳特
Look at Snart.
他成为罪犯是因为他的父亲是路易斯
He's a criminal because he had Lewis for a father.
我也可能变成那样
That could have been me.
那是不可能的
Oh, come on. Never.
是啊  那是因为我有你
Yeah, because I had you.
爱瑞丝也是
And so did Iris.
你要相信这一点  然后
You just gotta trust in that and
告诉她真相
tell her the truth.
怎么做才能不伤害到她呢
Yeah, how do I do that without hurting her?
她已经不是小女孩了
She's not a little girl anymore.
你应该看看她那天是怎么做的
You should have seen her in action the other day,
为了报道不惜冒那么大的风险
putting her neck on the line for a story.
她现在遇到什么事都能从容应对
She can handle anything that comes her way.
可是我骗了她太长时间
I just lied to her for so long,
我害怕她不能理解我  原谅我
I'm scared she's not gonna understand or forgive me.
那样我会失去她的
I could lose her.
不会的  她会原谅你的
No, she's gonna forgive you.
你只需要给她一个机会
You just gotta give her a chance.
我们九点行动
We make our move at 9:00.
这个点清洁员会进去
That's when the cleaning crews go in
而且白班的员工也会下班
and the daytime shift leaves.
我们坐员工电梯到27楼
Now we'll go up in the service elevator to the 27th floor.
从27楼到29楼每层会有两个武装保安
They got a two-man team of armed guards working the 27th through 29th floor,
可是如果能精确计算好他们的换班时间
but if we time it perfectly with their shift change,
我们就能进出自由了
we should be able to get in and out.
可如果计算得不精确呢
And if the timing doesn't work out?
那那些保安就回不了家了
Then those guards don't make it home.
可如果我们从顶层开始的话
But if we start on the top floor,
有个员工电梯可以...
there's a service elevator that will...
儿子  你我都清楚
Son, you and I both know
干这种事肯定得死一些人
that there's casualties in this line of work.
卢腾伯格  你是负责技术的
Rutenberg, you're the tech guy.
想到进入金库大厅的方法了吗
Did you find a solution for the vault hallway?
还没有
Not yet.
德雷肯系统的键盘是个问题
That Draycon Systems keypad's gonna be a problem.
好吧  那你呢
Fine. How about you?
你也要让我失望吗  还是说你的急冻枪
You gonna disappoint me too, or is that freeze gun of yours
能搞定激光束的电源呢
gonna look after the power source for the laser grid?
那叫冷冻枪  是的
It's a cold gun, and yes,
不过我有个更好的办法能穿过那些激光束
but I have a better way to get past the lasers.
就是因为有那把枪你才能来这里
That gun is the only reason you're here,
所以你还是闭嘴吧  免得我...
so shut up before I make you...
我的  我的头
Ow, my-- my head.
我的头
Oh! My head!
感觉要...
Feels like it's gonna...
没人可以跟我儿子这么说话
Nobody talks to my son that way.
没人可以
Nobody.
丹维尔市
肉类加工业
别担心  长官  这次我等你来了
Don't worry, sir. I waited for you this time.
好吧  我自己先做了一个简单的初步评估
Okay, I may have done a quick preliminary assessment of my own.
有些地方绝对很奇怪
Something is definitely weird.
斩首
Decapitation.
我们还在找尸体的头部
We're still recovering parts of the head,
所以确认身份的时间要比平常久一些
so the ID is taking a little longer than normal.
抱歉  我以为我踩到他的耳朵上了
Sorry, I thought I stepped on an ear.
我没有  如果是的话  我会听见动静的
I didn't. If I did, I'd be hearing things.
不是吧
Oh, hell no.
砍他头所用的武器不像是我所熟悉的
Doesn't look like the head was sliced off with any weapon I'm familiar with,
而大部分的武器我都熟悉
and I'm familiar with most weapons.
是的  你说得对
Yeah, you're right.
脖子周围有穿孔  很不整齐
Perforation around the neck-- it's too jagged.
非常像是头炸掉了
It's almost like the head was blown off.
就像是头能爆炸的超能力者  对吧
Like a meta-human who can explode heads, right?
也未必
Not necessarily.
有铝热剂残留
Traces of thermite.
炸弹的残留物吗
Bomb residue?
可为什么身体的其他部分没被炸掉
But then why wasn't the rest of the body blown apart?
我不知道
I don't know.
死者是大卫·卢腾伯格
The victim is David Rutenberg,
安保系统专家
security systems expert,
猜猜谁在他的已知同伙名单上
and guess who's on his list of known associates.
-路易斯·史纳特  -路易斯·史纳特
- Lewis Snart. - Lewis Snart.
他不是莱昂纳多·史纳特的亲人吗
Isn't he related to Leonard Snart,
也就是寒冷队长
AKA Captain Cold?
-别这么叫他  -好的
- Please don't call him that. - Okay.
-失陪一下  -好的
- Uh, one second. - Sure.
过来一下  我觉得这人是史纳特团伙中的
Come here. I think this guy is part of Snart's crew.
史纳特把炸弹放在他脑袋里从而让他听话吗
So Snart put a bomb in him to keep him in line?
不  史纳特不会那么做  可他父亲会
No, Snart wouldn't do that, but his father would.
路易斯杀了人
So Lewis is killing people,
而史纳特还在帮他吗
and Snart's still working with him?
你们不是有协议吗
What happened with the deal you had?
可能他也是被逼的
Maybe he doesn't have a choice.
你觉得路易斯在他儿子头里放了炸弹
So you think Lewis put a bomb in his own son
从而强迫他去抢劫吗
to force him to pull off a heist?
就算这样史纳特也不会做的
Snart still wouldn't do it.
真到万不得已他会把头里的炸弹挖出来
He'd dig the bomb out of his own head if he had to.
那一定是为了史纳特所在乎的什么事
So it must be something else that Snart cares about.
史纳特唯一在乎的就是他妹妹
The only thing Snart cares about is his sister.
我觉得你肯定会饿了
Thought you might be hungry.
还好无论到了哪个地球
Ah, good to know whatever Earth you go to,
都有大贝利汉堡店
there's always a Big Belly Burger.
非常感谢
Thank you very much.
看来你有所进展
Looks like you're making progress.
很慢  本来速度应该能更快点的
Slowly. Should be able to do this a lot faster.
你怀念你的速度吗
You miss it, your speed?
是的  很惊讶我会这么怀念
Yeah. Surprising how much.
那等你回到你的地球上后  你会怎么办
So what will you do when you go back to your Earth?
我不知道
I don't know.
我想我得慢慢适应成为
Guess I'll just have to get used to being--
普通人
Normal?
是的
Yeah.
两年前  我还只是一个
Two years ago, I was just a scientist
想要通过无残留辐射的净化重水
slowly trying to save the world by purifying heavy water
来拯救世界的科学家
without residual radiation.
很重要的工作
Important work.
是的  以前是
Yeah, it was,
可是在粒子加速器爆炸后
but after the Particle Accelerator exploded,
我不需要等好多年才能让我的研究去拯救生命
I didn't need to wait years for my research to save a life,
我在早饭前就能救一个人
I could save one before breakfast.
睡觉前我都能救50个人了
I could save 50 before going to sleep.
没有什么能像你们快
There's nothing like that rush.
你们经历了很多次战斗
You guys have been fighting so many battles,
一个接一个
one after another,
我不知道巴里有没有接受这个事实
I'm not sure Barry's had time to take it in,
对这种感觉充满感激
to appreciate how great it can feel.
成为超级英雄不在于你能跑多快
Being a superhero isn't always about how fast you can run.
而是无论什么情况你都能去帮别人
It's about helping however you can,
尤其是无论在哪都能帮助别人
wherever you're needed most.
我认为物理学家杰伊·加里克
I think that Jay Garrick, physicist,
会和超级英雄杰伊·加里克一样有作为
has just as much to contribute as Jay Garrick, superhero.
也许会更有作为
Maybe more.
你知道怎样会助我更快造好神速炮吗
You know what would help me build the speed cannon faster?
一位助手
An extra set of hands.
尤其是具备外科医生精密度品质的人
Specifically ones with a surgeon's precision.
我
Me?
要是你觉得我真能帮的上  没问题
Sure, if you think I can really help.
凯特琳
Hey, Caitlin?
快上来  这里需要你
We need you up here, like, right now.
抱歉
Sorry.
我的天
Oh, boy.
怎么了
What is it?
丽萨  你皮肤上有铝热剂的痕迹
Lisa, there are traces of thermite on your skin.
铝热剂
Thermite?
具有爆炸性
Like an explosive?
不是具有爆炸性
Not like an explosive.
就是个炸弹
It's a bomb.
你被击晕后
When you were knocked out,
你爸爸肯定把它注入了你体内
your dad must have injected you with it.
什么事  老爸
Hey, Dad, what's up?
你这个神秘的人给我留了条含糊的留言
Your message was pretty cryptic, even for you.
宝贝  你先坐下
Hey, baby, I need you to sit down.
老爸  怎么了
Dad, what's going on?
好吧
Okay.
当我还是个巡警的时候
When I was still a beat cop,
我和搭档正在巡逻
me and my partner were on patrol,
这时无线电传来了这个派遣任务
and this dispatch came on the radio.
一个小女孩打来电话
A little girl had called in.
说她妈妈服了些药
She said her mom had taken some pills
然后醒不过来了
and she wouldn't wake up.
小女孩留下了地址
And the little girl gave the address.
是我家的地址
The address was mine.
我到这的时候
By the time I got here,
你母亲不省人事
your mother was unresponsive.
昏倒在沙发上
Passed out on the couch.
厨房里的火炉开着
And in the kitchen, the stove was on.
你就那么站在明火前
There you were, standing in front of an open flame.
要不是我及时赶到
If I hadn't gotten here when I did--
-等等  我妈妈  -你妈妈是个瘾君子
- Wait, my mom-- - Your mom was a drug addict.
类似事件发生过不止一次
This wasn't the first time something like that had happened.
我把弗朗辛送到了另一家戒毒所
I got Francine into another rehab,
几天后
and a couple days later,
她消失了
she was gone.
我到处找她  但作为警察的妻子
I looked everywhere for her, but wife of a cop,
她知道如何隐藏行踪
she knew how to disappear.
我无法忍受
I couldn't stand...
想到你成长时要被贴上
the thought of you growing up
被抛弃的标签
thinking you were abandoned.
夜晚入睡时还想着
Going to sleep at night thinking
母亲的离去是因为自己不足以让她留下
your mother left because you weren't enough to make her stay,
想着自己不是被爱着的
that you weren't loved,
这一切都源于我对你的爱
because I loved you.
我倾尽所有去爱你
I loved you with everything I got.
后来我们收留了巴里
Then we took Barry in,
我看到了他经受的创伤  我
and I saw the trauma he was going through and I--
我确信
I was sure.
I was sure...
自己做了正确的事
that I did the right thing.
不让你承受那样的负担
Not giving you that burden.
你说妈妈离开了是什么意思  我
What do you mean mom left? I--
我不明白
I don't-- I don't understand.
我不明白你说这些是什么意思
I don't understand. What are you telling me?
你妈妈还活着
Your mother's alive.
她就在这  在中城
She's here in Central City.
她想见你
She wants to see you.
这么多年了  我还以为
All these years, I thought--
爸爸  你是说我的
Daddy, you told me that my--
我可以理解
I know.
我本该早点告诉你
I should have told you sooner,
可是我不知道如何开口
but I couldn't figure out the right way.
你记忆中的那个妈妈
The mother you thought you remember--
那个完美的母亲和我给你编造的故事
the perfect mother and the stories I made up for you--
才是你本该拥有的
that is the mother you deserve,
我知道弗朗辛做不到那些
and I knew Francine couldn't be like that.
她只会让你伤心
She would only break your heart.
真是对不起
I'm so sorry.
爸爸
Dad...
没关系  我懂
It's okay. I understand.
你是在保护我
You were just trying to keep me safe.
微型炸弹壳体一定是
The micro-bomb casing must be made
由某种铁磁性材料制成
of some kind of a ferromagnetic material.
只要你稳稳拿住磁体
Once you hold it steady with the magnet,
我就能像做外科手术一样切除它
I can surgically excise it.
放下磁体
Put the magnet down!
这是个十分浓缩的炸弹
This is a really concentrated bomb.
暴露在磁性摩擦和氧化剂下
It's gonna combust if it's exposed
就会燃烧
to magnetic friction and an oxidant.
他是什么意思
What's he talking about?
空气
Air.
炸弹接触了空气就会发生爆炸
Uh, the bomb will explode if it comes in contact with air.
别担心  丽萨
Don't worry, Lisa.
我们会找到别的方法把它取出来
We're gonna find another way to get it out.
科学家们  我们来商量下好吗
Scientific minds. Can we confer, please.
让闪电侠快速把它提取出来怎么样
What if Flash speed extracts it?
不行  太冒险了
Nope, it's too risky.
我会找到办法把它取出来的
I'm gonna find a way to get it out.
只是需要点时间
I just need a little time.
你找到拆除炸弹的办法前
Well, we need to keep track of Lewis
我们得盯着路易斯
until you figure out how to disarm the bomb.
多希望我们知道他接下来要偷什么  何时去偷
I wish we knew what he was gonna steal next and when.
或许我可以让他们告诉我
Maybe I can get them to tell me.
他们的技术人员死了
Their tech guy is dead,
我敢打赌他们需要个新的
so I'm betting they're gonna need a new one.
我是说我要渗入路易斯队伍内部
I'm saying I'm gonna infiltrate Lewis' crew.
你要打扮成个罪犯
You're gonna pretend to be a criminal?
轻而易举
How hard can it be?
怎么老是你
These visits are getting old.
这次会交好运
Third time's a charm.
跟你说了  我不需要拯救
I told you, I don't need saving.
但你妹妹需要
But your sister does.
我知道你爸爸在丽萨体内放了炸弹
I know your dad put a bomb in Lisa.
路易斯跟你说
Lewis told you he'd kill her
如果你不帮他  他就杀了她  对吧
if you didn't help him, right?
别担心
Look don't worry.
小组的人正在设法移除那个炸弹
My team's working on a way to remove the bomb.
希望你的那把枪准备好开火了
I hope you got that gun of yours ready to blast
因为...
'cause...
他是谁
Who the hell's this?
兰尼说你们需要新的技术员
Um, Lenny said you needed new tech.
你好  我叫山姆...
What's up, I'm Sam, so...
别告诉我你觉得这个小子
You tellin' me you think this kid
能破解德雷肯的键盘锁
can crack a Draycon keypad?
去年我帮史纳特把康达克王朝钻石
Uh, I did help Snart steal the Kahndaq Dynasty Diamond
从中城博物馆偷出来的
from Central City Museum last year.
它锁在阿美特克军工企业三阶抑制门里面
That was locked up behind an AmerTek Industries
用的就是德雷肯XL-1218型号的键盘锁
Phase Three Suppression Door with a Draycon XL-1218 keypad.
所以...
So...
没他的帮忙是偷不出来的
Couldn't have done it without him.
德雷肯是我的强项
Draycon's my jam.
好吧  山姆  走吧
Okay, Sam. Let's go.
现在就走啊
Right now?
你有什么问题吗
You got a problem with that?
没问题  迫不及待了
No, all good. Can't wait.
这一定会很有意思的
Oh, this should be fun.
闭上嘴  跟着我走
Keep quiet and follow my lead.
跟以前一样
Just like old times.
你们在看钻石队的比赛啊
You watching the Diamonds' game?
是啊  火蜥蜴队要赢了
Yeah, the Salamanders are killing 'em.
身份卡
IDs.
你们去哪层楼
What floor are you going to?
27楼
27th.
怎么那么慢啊  伙计们
Hey, what's the hold up, guys?
你们想给经理打电话
I mean, you wanna call management
解释为什么洗手间还是堵着的吗
and explain why the toilets are still overflowing?
我们很赶时间  知道吗
We're all on the clock, right?
好了  你们可以进去了
Yeah, you guys are good to go.
谢谢
Thanks.
你们好好看吧
You enjoy the game, guys.
钻石队不可能胜出的
Diamonds don't stand a chance.
今晚赢不赢还不一定
Not tonight they don't.
等等  你听见了吗
Hold on. Did you hear that?
我来
I got it.
有两个武装警卫
It's two armed guards.
我猜你的时间算得也不是每次都准啊
Guess your timing didn't work out after all.
是的  所以我才准备了后备计划
Yeah, that's why I got a Plan B.
因为你总会需要后备计划
'Cause you always needed one.
是啊  不过...
Yeah, but...
没想到你妹妹还是让我很失望
your sister turned out to be a disappointment also.
你们觉得我们继续进行怎么样
All right, what do you guys say we get on with the job?
警卫走了  可能去休息了
Guards are gone. Must have taken a break.
是啊  一定是
Yeah, must have.
好了  山姆
Okay, Sam.
让我们看看你的本事吧
Show us what you got.
是啊  我要...
Yeah, all right. Gonna just--
你们帮我把风  我来...
You guys just keep a lookout and I'll...
准许进入
跟你说了德雷肯是我强项
Told you Draycon was my jam.
-干得不错  山姆  -是吧
- Nice job, Sam. - Yeah.
能死在最开心的时候挺好
It's good to go out on a high note.
对不起  巴里
I'm sorry, Barry.
你想用那东西对我做什么
What are you gonna do to me with that thing?
它的控制压力达到一千压强以上时
Operating pressure on this is over 1,000 PSI.
只需一枪高能射击
This will easily suck the micro-bomb
它就能轻而易举的把微型炸弹
out of her neck and into the barrel of this
从你脖子吸到枪桶里
with one high-powered shot.
要冒一个很小的风险
There is one slight risk.
用高能武器直击我的脖子
Besides shooting a high-powered weapon
还不算冒险吗
directly against my neck?
这把枪用得是压缩空气
The gun does use compressed air.
我相信你  西斯科
I trust you, Cisco.
好了  儿子  让我骄傲一次吧
Okay, son. Make me proud.
谁稀罕
Like I care.
现在怎么做
Ha, now what?
我告诉过你我有更好的办法通过激光防护
I told you, I had a better way past the lasers.
靠边站  该给你再上一课了
Step aside. Time for another lesson.
系统解冻前  你有125秒钟的时间
You've got 125 seconds before the system defrosts.
-然后呢  -警报会响
- Then what? - Sirens.
你感觉怎么样
How do you feel?
就像是要取出炸弹的感觉
Like we should have put down some plastic.
这并不可笑
It's not funny.
是的
Yeah...
不过我喜欢看你笑
but I like it when you smile.
好了  准备好了吗
Okay, ready?
开枪  西斯科
Shoot me, Cisco.
是闪电侠
It's--d--Flash!
西斯科  丽萨怎么样了
Cisco, how's it going with Lisa?
正在关键时刻呢  伙计
Uh, kind of in the middle of it right now, buddy!
好吧  我们需要拿出那个炸弹
All right, we need that bomb out.
抢劫马上就会失败
The heist is going down right now.
时间到了
Time's up.
快离开这里
Let's get out of here.
你唯一能回的地方就是铁山监狱  路易斯
Only place you're going is back to Iron Heights, Lewis.
-你想打赌吗  -我想打赌吗
- Ah, you wanna bet? - Do I wanna bet?
别打赌  给我一分钟
Do not bet! Give me a minute.
你告诉我  什么样的人
Tell me this, what kind of man
会把炸弹放在自己女儿身体里
puts a bomb in his own daughter?
一个非常富有的人
A very rich man.
开枪射他  儿子
Shoot him, son.
杀了他  否则你就别想活着见到你妹妹
Kill him or you'll never see your sister alive.
开枪  西斯科
Do it, Cisco.
我取出炸弹了
I got the bomb out!
丽萨安全了
Lisa's safe.
你跟闪电侠合作了吗
You're working with The Flash?
我以为你恨他
I thought you hated him?
但是我...
Not as much as I...
更恨你
hate you.
丽萨安全了
Lisa was safe.
你为什么要那样做
Why did you do that?
他伤了我妹妹的心
He broke my sister's heart.
只有这样才公平
Only fair I break his.
上次来铁山监狱是看我爸爸
Last time I was in Iron Heights, I was visiting my Dad.
是啊  我也是
Yeah, me too.
-而你杀了他  -他活该
- And yet you killed him. - He deserved it.
你觉得有意思吗
Is that funny to you?
并不
No.
有意思的是我终于知道了你的秘密
What's funny is I finally figured out your secret.
什么秘密
And what secret would that be?
为了保护你妹妹  你不惜做任何事
You'd do anything to protect your sister.
我也知道你的秘密了
Well, I know your secret too.
你最好希望我别在睡觉的时候说出来
Better hope I don't talk in my sleep.
你不会的
You won't.
今天只是证明了我一直都知道的一件事
Today just proved what I've always known.
你有善良的一面  史纳特
There's good in you, Snart.
你不必向我承认
And you don't have to admit it to me,
但你内心知道
but there's a part of you that knows
不必让自己的过去来定义你
you don't have to let your past define you.
你内心真正想要做的事
A part of you that really wants
不止是成为一名罪犯
to be more than just a criminal.
难道我应该像你一样成为英雄吗  巴里
So I should be a hero like you, Barry?
再说一次  那活到底有多少钱
What exactly does that pay again?
只是时间的问题
It's just a matter of time.
你在这里会有很多时间的
Something you'll have a lot of in here.
没你想的那么多
Not as much as you think.
后会有期
Be seeing you.
你真的认为人会改变本性吗
You really think that leopard's gonna change its spots?
会的
I do.
也许我们该把他列入超能力者阵营
Maybe we should transfer him to the meta-human wing anyway.
我已经叫帕蒂着手去办了
I already got Patty on the paperwork.
我想谢谢你
Hey, I wanted to thank you
给我的建议
for the advice you gave.
我和爱瑞丝说了
I told Iris.
她会和弗朗辛好好谈谈
She's gonna sit down with Francine.
虽然很难接受  但是这是最好的结果
It was hard, but it was for the best.
很高兴帮到你  不客气
I'm glad. Any time.
-你是个好儿子  巴里  -我知道
- You're a good son, Barry. - I know.
谢谢
Thank you.
想不到在这里见到你
Fancy seeing you here.
我们不能再这样巧遇了
We have to stop running into each other like this.
我知道  我们应该安排一下时间
I know, we should just make a schedule or something.
好极了  那我就
Okay, great. Well, then I'll just have,
让我的手下联系你的手下
you know, my people call your people.
问题来了  我们俩都没有手下
See, that's the problem. Neither one of us have people.
那要怎么办呢
So how are we possibly gonna do this?
给  这是我的号码
There. My number.
你是这意思吧
That's what you meant, right?
是的
Yes, it--
-不是  -我
- No. - Yea--I--
你不是这意思
No you didn't.
不如这样吧
Um, you know what, though?
其实我一直想把我号码给你
I've actually been meaning to give you my number
万一你对案子有疑问呢
in case you had questions about a case.
有时接通调度中心电话时
You know, sometimes when you call through dispatch,
线路却不畅通
it gets all jammed up--
这样很有效率
And this is efficient.
同样身为一名执法人员
And as law enforcement colleagues,
-效率很重要  -没错
- efficiently is important. - Yes, it is.
不  我就是这么想的
No, that's a-- yeah-- that's exactly what I was thinking too.
好的  太好了
'Kay, great. Awesome.
好  回头见
Okay, I'll see you.
好
Yeah.
说笑的
Just kidding.
好的  谢谢
Okay. Thanks.
没事
Yep.
要走了吗
So, taking off?
想说句再见和谢谢
Thought I'd say good-bye and thank you.
我不会在任何人体内放炸弹的
Yeah, well, I wouldn't leave a bomb in anyone.
-包括你  -不止这些
- Not even you. - It's more than that.
当我觉得软弱时  你在身边陪着我
You were there for me when I was feeling weak.
我讨厌软弱的感觉
I hate feeling weak.
让我很难相信人
It's hard for me to trust people.
可我却相信你
I trusted you.
也许你会成为我第一个真正的朋友
You know, you might actually be my first real friend.
这里面有真心话吗
Is any of that true?
下次见  西斯科
Till next time, Cisco.
回头见  金色滑翔者
Later, Golden Glider.
神速炮
The Speed Cannon.
大家快看
Look at that.
你们真的做出来了
Dudes, you actually built the thing.
加里克先生  最近在我身体抱恙期间
Mr. Garrick, I am quiet impressed by what you've accomplished
你完成了很了不起的事
during my recent wellness hiatus.
-你们测试过没  -还没
- Have you tested it out yet? - Not yet.
你要试试吗
You wanna do the honors?
不不不  现在我
No, no, no, no. Now that I, uh--
现在我的健康恢复到了最佳状态
now that I am back to optimum health,
-让我来  -你
- please allow me. - Oh, would you--
精彩
Excelsior!
-你怎么让它稳定下来  -色味连锁相夸克物质
- How did you stabilize it? - CFL Quark Matter.
负能量密度与正表面压力
Negative energy density with positive surface pressure.
太聪明了
That's genius.
你做出了色味连锁相夸克物质
You created CFL Quark Matter?
我的地球在这方面的技术已经很完善了
It's something we perfected on my Earth.
有空告诉你们
I'll show you sometime.
你说的有空指的是几分钟之后吗
You mean, sometime in the next few minutes?
看来是时候了
Oh, yeah I guess this is it?
-我是时候回家了  -现在吗
- Time for me to go back home. - Right now?
缺口方面  我们还需要你的帮忙
I mean we still need your help with the Breachers.
我的首要任务是极速
My first priority is Zoom.
我要查明他的意图
I need to find out what he's up to.
用什么方法偷走我的速度
How he stole my speed.
在这里你也可以查
But you can do that here and,
如果你回去了
you know, if you go back,
我们需要你
then we can't get in touch with you
帮忙对付极速时
when we need your help or...
就没法和你联系
with Zoom or whatever else.
时不时能向人请教
It would be nice to be able to pick your brain
交流更多的极速心得
every once in a while,
也很不错
get some more speedster tips.
好  一旦打倒了极速
Okay... once we take care of Zoom,
-我就回家  -好
- I'm going home. - That's fair.
太好了  因为我要洗澡  刮刮胡子
Good, 'cause I could use a shower, a shave,
再晒晒太阳
and some sunlight.
晚点见
I'll, uh, see you later.
斯泰因教授  你的身体怎么样
So, Professor Stein, how are you feeling?
看来
Well, it appears
小憩把所有的病症都治愈了
that a little rest heals all maladies.
我感觉不到
I-I-I couldn't feel--
-教授  -不不不  别过去
- Professor? - No, no, no, no get back. Come here.
斯泰因教授  斯泰因教授
Professor Stein! Professor Stein!
听得到吗  斯泰因教授
Can you hear me, Professor Stein?
他怎么了  他变成了火风暴
What happened to him? He went up like Firestorm,
但是火焰为什么是蓝色的
but the flame, why was it blue?
我不知道  但是看来不妙
I don't know. This isn't good.
我们要快点稳定他的情况
We need to stabilize him fast.